Guide to the Jean Webster Papers, 1876–1982 (bulk 1900-1916)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series XI. Memorabilia
  - Jean Webster McKinney and Family
    - Biographical Material
      - Biographical notes collected from various Vassar College sources, n.d.; (MS, 20 p.) (Folder 39.4)
      - Biographical notes by Mary MacColl, VC 1898, for Dictionary of American Biography, 1933; (MS, 80 p.) (Folder 39.5)
      - Biographical note by Ethelyn McKinney, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 39.6)
      - Residences — Tyringham, MA; Loch Willow Farm, VA; and Tymor Farm, NY, (4 items) (Folder 39.7)
      - Authors' League of America material, 1913-1915; (4 items) (Folder 39.8)
      - Calling cards and printing plate, name labels, (16 items) (Folder 39.9)
    - Material Relating to Vassar College
      - Vassar Verse, Miscellany contest, "English A,", ca. 1901; (5 items) (Folder 39.10)
      - Advertisments for 1901 Vassarion, Class Day information, "Praise to Alma Mater" lyrics, (7 items) (Folder 39.11)
    - Wedding of Jean Webster and Glenn Ford McKinney
      - Wedding invitations and calling cards, 1915; (7 items) (Folder 39.12)
      - Placecards from wedding breakfast, postcards of Washington, CT, etc., 1915; (9 items) (Folder 39.13)
  - Material Relating to Jean Webster's Stories and Plays
    - Poster fragment advertising Jerry Junior, ca. 1907; (1 oversized item) (Folder 51.3)
    - Book jackets for Daddy Long-Legs, not first edition, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 40.1)
    - Sheet music: "My Daddy Long-Legs," words by E. Ray Goetz, music by Bert Grant, n.d.; (6 p. oversized) (Folder 51.2)
    - Inscription accompanying picture of Jean Webster given to Stamford Children's Home, 1918; (2 items) (Folder 40.2)
  - Trips Taken by Jean Webster McKinney
    - Entrance ticket to Vatican, 1900; (1 item) (Folder 40.3)
    - World Tour — Egypt — postcards, Dec 1906; (2 items) (Folder 40.4)
    - World Tour — Japan — postcards, small prints, Apr-June 1907; (4 items) (Folder 40.5)
    - World Tour — Japan — small prints, Apr-June 1907; (4 items) (Folder 40.6)
    - World Tour — Japan — Print, Apr-June 1907; (1 item) (Folder 51.1)
    - Ireland — postcards, summer 1912; (30 items) (Folder 40.7)
    - Ireland — postcards, summer 1912; (30 items) (Folder 40.8)
    - Ireland — postcards, summer 1912; (30 items) (Folder 40.9)
    - Ireland — postcards, summer 1912; (39 items) (Folder 40.10)
    - Scotland — postcards, summer 1912; (17 items) (Folder 41.1)
  - Sketches by Jean Webster
    - watercolor, line drawings, etc., n.d.; (8 items) (Folder 41.2)
  - Realia
    - Pocket-sized calendars, 1914, 1916; (3 items) (Folder 41.3)
    - Blank greeting cards, n.d.; (14 items) (Folder 41.4)
    - Advertisments, etc. — tobacco and cigars; railway drinking cup; "Papier Pouch,", (3 items) (Folder 41.5)
    - Black/orange grosgrain ribbon belt w/ "91" embroidered on it, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 41.6)
    - Gold/black "Votes for Women" banner, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 41.7)
    - Miscellaneous — 2 pencils, clothes label embroidered "JW," leaf impressions (?), n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 41.8)
- Series XII. Lady Jane Grey School Material
  - The Mosaic, Lady Jane Grey School newsletter, 1890-1899; (3 items) (Folder 42.1)
  - The Mosaic, Lady Jane Grey School newsletter, 1913-1918; (3 items) (Folder 42.2)
  - The Mosaic, Lady Jane Grey School newsletter, 1919-1920; (2 items) (Folder 42.3)
  - The Mosaic, Lady Jane Grey School newsletter, 1921-1923; (2 items) (Folder 42.4)
  - Christmas newsletter, 1914-1923; (8 items) (Folder 42.5)
  - Christmas newsletter, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 42.6)
  - Commencement addresses, 1906-1912, n.d.; (5 items) (Folder 42.7)
  - Lady Jane Grey School catalogue, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 42.8)
  - "Acting Under Difficulties," a play by Jane Brewster Hyde, (TS, 19 p.) (Folder 42.9)
  - Photocopies of Mary Hyde's photograph album, n.d.; (9 p.) (Folder 42.10)
  - Miscellaneous information about Lady Jane Grey School, 1903-1979, n.d.; (6 items) (Folder 42.11)
  - Miscellaneous information about Binghamton, NY, 1900-1933, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 42.12)
- Series XIII. Adelaide Crapsey Material
  - Biographical Material
    - Newspaper clippings, etc., 1914-1939, n.d.; (12 items) (Folder 45.17)
  - Correspondence
    - Letters from Adelaide Crapsey
      - F.A. Stokes Company, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 43.1)
      - G.P. Putnam's Sons, n.d.; (2 items) (Folder 43.1)
      - Professor Grandgent, (1 item) (Folder 43.1)
      - Webster, Jean, 1914; (3 items) (Folder 43.1)
    - Letters from Adelaide Trowbridge Crapsey
      - McKinney, Ethelyn, 1934-1938; (5 items) (Folder 43.2)
      - McKinney, Jean, 1927-1930; (3 items) (Folder 43.3)
    - Letters from Susan Sutton Smith [Adelaide Crapsey's biographer]
      - Connor, Ralph and Jean McKinney, 1973-1975; (9 items) (Folder 43.4)
  - Adelaide Crapsey's Poetry
    - Photocopies
      - Miscellaneous lists, etc., n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 43.5)
      - Adventure, n.d. (Folder 43.6)
      - Arbutus, n.d. (Folder 43.7)
      - Aubade, n.d. (Folder 43.8)
      - Autumn, n.d. (Folder 43.9)
      - "The Blessed Queen of heaven...,", n.d. (Folder 43.10)
      - "Bridget! Saint Bride!...,", n.d. (Folder 43.11)
      - Cinquains, n.d. (Folder 43.12)
      - Clotilda Sings, n.d. (Folder 43.13)
      - The Companions, n.d. (Folder 43.14)
      - Cradle-Song, n.d. (Folder 43.15)
      - The Crucifixion, n.d. (Folder 43.16)
      - The Death of Holofernes, n.d. (Folder 43.17)
      - Dirge, n.d. (Folder 43.18)
      - Dooms-day, n.d. (Folder 43.19)
      - The Elgin Marbles, n.d. (Folder 43.20)
      - The Entombment, n.d. (Folder 43.21)
      - Epigram, n.d. (Folder 43.22)
      - The Expulsion, n.d. (Folder 43.23)
      - Fate Defied, n.d. (Folder 43.24)
      - The Fiddler, n.d. (Folder 43.25)
      - For Lucas Cranach's Eve, n.d. (Folder 44.1)
      - Girl Fleeing Love, n.d. (Folder 44.2)
      - Grain Field, n.d. (Folder 44.3)
      - The Grand Canyon (Folder 44.4)
      - The Guarded Wound (Folder 44.5)
      - Harvester's Song, n.d. (Folder 44.6)
      - "How can you lie so still...,", n.d. (Folder 44.7)
      - "How doth blue...,", n.d. (Folder 44.8)
      - The Immortal Residue, n.d. (Folder 44.9)
      - "It's oh, my dear...,", n.d. (Folder 44.10)
      - Lament, n.d. (Folder 44.11)
      - Langour After Pain, n.d. (Folder 44.12)
      - Lines Adressed to my Left Lung, n.d. (Folder 44.13)
      - Lo, All the Way, n.d. (Folder 44.14)
      - The Lonely Death, n.d. (Folder 44.15)
      - Lunatick, n.d. (Folder 44.16)
      - Madness, n.d. (Folder 44.17)
      - Milking Time, n.d. (Folder 44.18)
      - The Mourner, n.d. (Folder 44.19)
      - Narcissus, n.d. (Folder 44.20)
      - "Never did love...,", n.d. (Folder 44.21)
      - Niagara, n.d. (Folder 44.22)
      - Night Winds (Folder 44.23)
      - Oh, Lady, let the sad tears fall, n.d. (Folder 44.24)
      - The Parting, n.d. (Folder 44.25)
      - The Plaint, n.d. (Folder 44.26)
      - The Pledge, n.d. (Folder 44.27)
      - The Proud Poet, n.d. (Folder 44.28)
      - Refuge in Darkness (Folder 44.29)
      - The Refusal, n.d. (Folder 44.30)
      - Roma Aeterna, n.d. (Folder 44.31)
      - Saranac Lake, n.d. (Folder 45.1)
      - Saying, n.d. (Folder 45.2)
      - The Shroud, n.d. (Folder 45.3)
      - Song, n.d. (Folder 45.4)
      - The Song of Choice, n.d. (Folder 45.5)
      - The Source, n.d. (Folder 45.6)
      - Stephan..., n.d. (Folder 45.7)
      - The Sun Dial (Folder 45.8)
      - Susanna and the Elders (Folder 45.9)
      - There's a Gay Girl Laughing, n.d. (Folder 45.10)
      - To A Hermit Thrush, n.d. (Folder 45.11)
      - To An Unfaithful Lover, n.d. (Folder 45.12)
      - Vendor's Song (Folder 45.13)
      - The Warning, n.d. (Folder 45.14)
      - Warning to the Mighty, n.d. (Folder 45.15)
      - You Nor I Nor Nobody Knows, n.d. (Folder 45.16)
    - Originals — Restricted Material
      - Miscellaneous lists, etc., n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 46.1)
      - Adventure, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.2)
      - Arbutus, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.3)
      - Aubade, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.4)
      - Autumn, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.5)
      - "The blessed Queen of Heaven...,", n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.6)
      - "Bridget! Saint Bride!...,", n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.7)
      - Cinquains, n.d.; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 46.8)
      - Clotilda Sings, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.9)
      - The Companions, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.10)
      - Cradle-Song, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.11)
      - The Crucifixion, n.d.; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 46.12)
      - The Death of Holofernes, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.13)
      - Dirge, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.14)
      - Dooms-day, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.15)
      - The Elgin Marbles, n.d.; (TS/MS, 3 p.) (Folder 46.16)
      - The Entombment, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.17)
      - Epigram, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.18)
      - The Expulsion, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.19)
      - Fate Defied, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.20)
      - The Fiddler, n.d.; (MS, 6 p.) (Folder 46.21)
      - For Lucas Cranach's Eve, n.d.; (TS/MS, 2 p.) (Folder 46.22)
      - Girl Fleeing Love, n.d.; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.23)
      - Grain Field, n.d.; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 46.24)
      - The Grand Canyon, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.25)
      - The Guarded Wound, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.26)
      - Harvester's Song, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.27)
      - "How can you lie so still...,", n.d.; (MS, 6 p.) (Folder 46.28)
      - "How doth blue...,", n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.29)
      - The Immortal Residue, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.30)
      - "It's oh, my dear...,", n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.31)
      - Lament, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.32)
      - Langour After Pain, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.33)
      - Lines Adressed to my Left Lung, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.34)
      - Lo, All the Way, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.35)
      - The Lonely Death, n.d.; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 46.36)
      - Lunatick, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.37)
      - Madness, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.38)
      - Milking Time, n.d.; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 46.39)
      - The Mourner, n.d.; (MS/TS, 2 p.) (Folder 46.40)
      - Narcissus, n.d.; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 46.41)
      - "Never did love...,", n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.42)
      - Niagara, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.43)
      - Night Winds, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 46.44)
      - Oh, Lady, let the sad tears fall, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.1)
      - The Parting, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.2)
      - The Plaint, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.3)
      - The Pledge, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.4)
      - The Proud Poet, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.5)
      - Refuge in Darkness, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.6)
      - The Refusal, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.7)
      - Roma Aeterna, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.8)
      - Saranac Lake, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.9)
      - Saying, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.10)
      - The Shroud, n.d.; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.11)
      - Song, n.d.; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 47.12)
      - The Song of Choice, n.d.; (MS, 8 p.) (Folder 47.13)
      - The Source, n.d.; (TS/MS, 2 p.) (Folder 47.14)
      - Stephan..., n.d.; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 47.15)
      - The Sun Dial, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.16)
      - Susanna and the Elders, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.17)
      - There's a Gay Girl Laughing, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.18)
      - To A Hermit Thrush, n.d.; (TS/MS, 2 p.) (Folder 47.19)
      - To an Unfaithful Lover, n.d.; (TS/MS, 2 p.) (Folder 47.20)
      - Vendor's Song, (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.21)
      - The Warning, n.d.; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 47.22)
      - Warning to the Mighty, n.d.; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 47.23)
      - You Nor I Nor Nobody Knows, n.d.; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 47.24)